Welcome to another video and in this video. We are going to discuss one of the one of the important topic called a C name to pipe
Okay, so the name itself is very different. It's a name to pipe
so
Let's start our discussion
So we already discussed if the threat actor want to do any changes in the registry or do anything in the operating system
So they need a high elevator privilege or to do the operations, right?
So we already did a
Medium to high integrity privilege, but we need to transfer our privilege escalation to high-to system integrity. Okay, so here
I draw some
diagram this is a client and this is a service provider
So let in the same time. I will give the example for a name to pipe. Okay
So why we are using the name to pipe based attack?
So the attacks like name to pipe impersonation. So what is a name to pipe? Okay?
So name to pipe was one of the windows feature that was introduced in
Microsoft windows and
That named by pause used for
Communicating with communicating to process. Okay, so let's consider there was a two process
Let's say there's a set to the land a bit certain in this two process one to communicate with each other
They will you they this two process will use the name to pipe for a communication. Okay, so basically
If the third you will want to transfer some data to the bits admin it will use a
Name to pipe, okay, or or if the bits admin want to transfer some message to your third you till it will use a named to pipe
To your transfer, okay, either it will transfer through a file or a network
So this is called as a named pipe. So named to pipe is basically introduced for a process communication
So communicate between two process
The windows windows
Microsoft windows introduced to the future. Okay
For every operating system, okay
So let's talk about how how we can elevate our privilege using the name to pipe, okay?
So let's come to the diagram. So here you can see one of the one of the pew man
and he's
And
He's a client
And this is a service provider. Okay, so let's take service provider as a
MySQL server
So it's a MySQL server. Okay, so this is a client or a user. So let's take client or a
User so if the user or a client want to query the MySQL
So what he will do he will
Use a
Particular language always query or some other MySQL query to query the MySQL server, right?
So this that's that's a basic programming. So if you want to
If the user want to take any data from the MySQL server, he will query the database, right? He will query some program select star from
Users it will display all the users, right? Instead the MySQL
So let's take
The user only have a low level privilege. Okay, so user only have the low level privilege
Absolutely our service provider will have some high integrity level privilege because
It can able to interact with the every database inside it, right? So once the user
User user gives some query
To the service provider this service provider will verify the user. Okay, so if the user only have a low integrity level
So if or some of the low integrity level user
Only can able to query the database. Okay, he can view the users
He can view a particular column or he can view some information in the database. Okay
So only he can he can query the database. Okay, he can get only the information
He can't able to delete or he can't able to modify or he can't able to add any table or column in the database
Okay, so the service provider will take the user level user privilege. Okay, so user user privilege and it will
Rend the query as a user. Okay, so this is the intermediate between the
Client and the client or user or the and the MySQL server. Okay, this service provider will take the user level privilege
User privilege and it will verify that privilege. So if the user only can able to
Query the database
The user access control was only query the database. It will
It will only query the database. Okay, it will only do they give the information
Based on the privilege. Okay, so let's say if the
Let's think about this user. Okay, so let's say we'll delete the user and I will remove everything
From here
So this is a superman user
Okay, this is a superman user and not a superman. He's a spider-man and he has a privilege
Sorry
He's one of the user
So I already discussed the service provider have has one of the privilege right the service provider has a
One of the privilege it will take the user privilege and it will
execute the query
What the
Based on the user privilege right based on the user privilege. Okay
So let's say the service provider has a privilege. Okay
And this client have a very high level privilege. Okay, very
High level privilege then the service provider. Okay, so the service provider only have a high level privilege
But this client or user have a very high level privilege. This is the very high level privilege in the sense
The privilege was greater than this service provider. So now what service provider will do
So if I'm a service provider, I will I will abuse this
Client or user privilege to do some activities. Okay, so let's say the service provider only can able to
Modify the data
Or add the data. Okay
But this spider-man this very high privilege user can able to add
Modify
As well as delete. Okay, he can able to delete the database. Okay, so now the service provider will
Because uh
This user this very high privilege user this spider-man need to interact
With this service provider, right to query the database to do something with the database. Okay. So now this service provider
Will get the user this spider-man privilege, right? We'll get this spider-man privilege. I mean the very high privilege. Okay
What he will do
He will query the database by querying this service provider will get the very high privilege
To add
Delete
And modify. Okay, by this
This uh, service provider will get a very high privilege
And he will do anything in the database. Okay, so it was called as the impersonation
Okay, named pipe impersonation. Okay. So let's take a example of a real real real time
So what it will do? Okay, I will I will explain this the example. Okay, this is a overall
Understanding of what is a named pipe. I will explain it in how the how it will happen inside the computer. Okay
So let's take as an example of our cobalt straight payload root ket remover. Okay, so let's take an example of our root ket remover
Dot exa. So what it will do it will create a
It will create a process with a high level privilege. Okay
For example, it's a run
DLL 32 dot exa wait a second
Yep, so now
Let's take an example of a root ket remover dot exa our cobalt strike payload
It created a rendial 32 dot exa as a system level privilege. Okay
So it created a
Rendial 32 dot exa system level privilege. We know the root ket remover will be the root ket remover will be the owner. Okay, because
We are the owner, right? So we only created the rendial 32 dot exa. Okay, so we are the server
Are we are the owner? Okay
So we created a
System level process rendial 32 dot exa system level privilege. Okay, so now what we we can we will do we are doing the same thing
What I said in the above diagram. We are using this very high level privilege
For our attack for doing our malicious activities. Okay, so now this is the owner
This is the server and the owner the root ket remover dot exa will be the server or a owner and the created process will be the
Running under the system level privilege. So automatically this root ket remover will got a very high level privilege
Right, so this is called as the named pipe impulse nation. Okay, so in a board diagram
I already discussed this user have a very high level privilege and if the service provider
Impose net abuse this very high level user privilege for a for doing a malicious activities
So in this scenario our house our client will be the rendial 32 dot exa
And our service provider will be our cobalt straight payload
Okay, so this is called as the named pipe impulse nation. Okay, so we will see how to do the named pipe impulse nation attack in a practical
Okay, in the next video. So this this
Theory video, but I hope I explained everything
Good way
So if you do not understand about this video if you do not understand so no problem. We will
We will see in the practical section. Okay
That's all about this video. We will meet on you. So we will meet you on the next video. Thank you. Thank you for watching